Siddhartha Sadhukhan (1) Featured

Developer seeking roles in Data Engineering, Big Data Developer, Software Development, Application Programming, Solution Architecture

Skills: Spark, Scala, Java, Python, Hive, SQL, Hadoop, Oozie, Shell-Script, NoSQL, Data

Structures, Algorithms.



Current Designation: Developer Total Experience: 3 Year(s) 2 Month(s)

Current Company: Mu Sigma Notice Period: 1 Month

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore Highest Degree: MCA [Computers]

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Hyderabad, Pune Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Software Developer, Software Development, Application Programming, Application Maintenance, Project

Management, Requirement Analysis, Solution Architecture, Data

Structures, Algorithms, Spark, Scala, Java, Python, Hive, SQL, Hadoop, Oozie, Shell-Script, NoSQL, Kafka

Verified: Email - id Phone Number |

Last Active: 21-Jan-21 Last Modified: 20-Jan-21

Summary

Self-driven Software professional, with an overall 3+ years of experience in Product Development.

Currently working at Mu-Sigma as a Developer.

Good knowledge in Big Data technologies Like Hadoop ecosystem, HDFS, Yarn, Spark, Kafka, Zookeeper, No-SQL.

Hands on experience in Azure Cloud.

Familiar with Windows, Linux, Git, SVN, Maven, CI/CD Process, Agile and Scrum methodology.

Business domain knowledge in Manufacturing, Financial Services and Technology.

Efficiently and effectively managed critical deliverables at the Software Engineering level, associated with communication and client-handling skills.

Interested in Coding, Data Structure, Algorithm, Solving challenges, R&D and Architectural Designing.

Willing to work on Large Scale Distributed Systems, Machine Learning.

Work Experience

Mu Sigma as Developer Feb 2020 to Till Date

Working as a Big Data Developer. Key Responsibilities: Development of new matrices, Defect fixing or changing on the existing matrices, POC,

Modification and creation of ADF pipeline to fit new execution flow.

Achievements: Optimized the pipeline which has decreased the storage cost by 20% and solved the storage throttling issue, Another optimization reduced the pipe line execution time by 5%, Developed CI/CD pipeline along with unit testing framework.

Wipro as Project Engineer Nov 2017 to Feb 2020

Worked as Software Engineer. Key Responsibilities: User story development, Defect fixing, POC and providing DevOps solution, Creation of production deployment script, Documentation as well as providing support. Achievements: Optimized the data pipeline which reduced the execution time by 15%, Introduced a file link at storage

level so that SAP and Liferay both can access the same data.

Education

UG: BCA (Computers) from Burdwan University in 2013

PG: MCA (Computers) from West Bengal University of Technology (WBUT) in 2016

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
SPARK			2 Year(s) 2 Month(s)
JAVA			
Python			
HIVE			
SQL			
HADOOP			
oozie			
SHELL-SCRIPT			
SCALA		0	2 Year(s) 2 Month(s)
Kafka		0	0 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Hindi				
Bengali				

Projects

Project Title: Admin Panel Data Processing Pipeline

Client: N/A

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Mar 2020 - Till Date Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Project Details: Spark is used to process the telemetry data of a leading communication and collaboration tool stored in

Azure Data Lake Storage Gen2 and processed date is stored to Cosmos DB.

Azure Databricks is used to execute the Spark jobs and workflows are defined using ADF.

Key Responsibilities:

Development of new matrices, Defect fixing or changing on the existing matrices, POC.

Modification and creation of ADF pipeline to fit new execution flow.

Achievements:

Optimized the pipeline which has decreased the storage cost by 20% and solved the storage throttling issue.

Another optimization reduced the pipe line execution time by 5%.

Developed CI/CD pipeline along with unit testing framework.

Project Title: Mosaic Data Transformation

Client: N/A

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Dec 2018 - Feb 2020

Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Project Details: Using Spark transformed the banking data stored in Hive table to produced input for a BI system.

Oozie is used to trigger different workflows in order.

Key Responsibilities:

User story Development, Defect Fixing, POC.

Creation of Production deployment script, Document as well as providing support.

Achievements:

Optimized the data pipeline which reduced the execution time by 15%.

Project Title: Non-Conformity Management System

Client: N/A

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Jan 2018 - Nov 2018

Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Project Details: Web application to manage Quality check process, accessible using REST API through JSON and XML

format.

Liferay is used to develop the application along with Spring and Hibernate framework.

Key Responsibilities:

Development of user stories, Defect fixing, POC and providing DevOps solution.

Achievements:

Introduced a file link at storage level so that SAP and Liferay both can access the same data.

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Physically Challenged: No Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time